You won't get away...this time...
今度は逃がさん。
Here he comes!
来るぞ。
(２人)はい。
- Right!
《速い…》
He's fast!
きゃあ！
くそっ！
Damn it!
《動けない…》
I can't move.
(角都)はたけ カカシ…。
Kakashi Hatake...
お前で 失った心臓の
補充をする気だったが➡
I was planning to replace the hearts
I lost with yours...
気が変わった。
but I changed my mind.
(角都)心臓の補充など➡
I can get more hearts anytime I want,
after all...
別に いつでもできるからな。
Die!
死ね！
風遁 螺旋丸。
Wind Style: Rasengan!
(ヤマト)水遁 破奔流。
Water Style: Ripping Torrent!
(ナルト/ヤマト)颶風水渦の術。
- Hurricane Vortex Jutsu!
遅くなって すまねえってばよ。
Sorry...we're late.
ふぅ… いいタイミングだ。
Perfect timing...
はぁ… 増援 助かった。
Thanks for the support...
サクラ サイさん ナルトも…。
Sakura...Sai...and Naruto.
(ヤマト)こんな かっこ悪い先輩は
初めて見ましたよ。
I've never seen you this beat.
(カカシ)悪かったな。
Sorry about that.
(ヤマト)この敵… 相当強いですね。
This enemy...must be pretty strong.
When You Curse Someone,
You Dig Your Own Grave
また おかしなのが来たな。
More strange people...
すでに ボロボロとは…。
And he is pretty messed up already...
ナルト 大丈夫なの？
シカマルは？
Naruto, are you okay?
Where is Shikamaru?
もう１人の敵と
別の場所で戦ってる。
He's a little ways off
fighting the other enemy.
シカマル側にも ２人向かってほしい。
I want two of you to
head towards Shikamaru.
遠距離タイプと医療タイプがいい。
Preferably, a long-distance fighter
and a medic.
(パックン)拙者に任せろ。
I'll take care of it.
よし！
サイとサクラは パックンの誘導に従い➡
All right!
Sai and Sakura follow Pakkun's lead
and support Shikamaru!
シカマルの援護に向かえ。
(サクラ)はい。
(サイ)はい。
Yes!
Yes.
フッ… 烏合の衆が 何をする。
Hah! What's this unorganized gang
trying to do?
抜きとる心臓の
バリエーションが増えただけだな。
Now there're more hearts for me
to choose from.
ハハハハ…。
こっからは オレがやるってばよ。
From here on, this one's mine.
ナルト…。
Naruto...
拙者たちも行くぞ。
We're off!
ナルト こっちは頼んだわよ。
Naruto, I leave it to you!
完成したのか？
Did you...complete it?
いえ… ５割程度です。
No...only about 50 percent.
そうか…。
I see...
けど…。
But...
(ヤマト)まあ 見ててください。
Well, just watch.
以前のナルトとは 別人ですよ。
Naruto is not the same person
he used to be.
こっちじゃ。
This way!
(サイ)いくらなんでも
あのアスマさんを殺した相手に➡
Either way... To go against an opponent
who killed Asuma alone...
１人で挑むなんて…。
大丈夫なのかな？
シカマルく… シカマルは。
Is Shikamaru-kun... I mean,
Shikamaru going to be all right?
シカマルは大丈夫。
Shikamaru is fine.
《彼は 火の国 随一の頭脳と➡
He is...the most intelligent Shinobi
in the Land of Fire.
それに…》
Plus...
((へい…
じゃあ 行ってくるとしますか。
Okay... Well then, let's go.
もう…
まったく やる気がないんだから。
Sheesh... He has absolutely no interest.
あれで 中隊長だっていうんだから
信じられない。
I can't believe he's a sub-captain.
(綱手)そう言うな。
Don't say that. It's difficult for him
to show any interest.
アイツは やる気を見せるのが苦手。
というより嫌いなんだろう。
In fact, I bet he hates showing it.
汗かきながら 一生懸命
めんどくさがってるのさ。
He's trying really hard
to show disinterest.
よく わかりません。
I don't get it...
Lady Tsunade, aren't you overrating him?
綱手様… シカマルのこと➡
過大評価しすぎなんじゃ
ないですか？
私は まだまだ
過小評価だと思ってるがな。
I think I am still underrating him...
(サクラ)これは？
This is...?
(綱手)火の国大名名義
正式な依頼状がきた。
We recently received an official offer
from a Feudal Lord in the Land of Fire...
シカマルを大名の近衛機関にほしい
とのことだ。
They want Shikamaru as a member of
the Feudal Lord's personal guard division.
この前の中忍試験での
シカマルの実行委員ぶりが➡
It seems Shikamaru's role
as an administrator during
the last Chunin exam
大名の周囲の者の目に
とまったようだ。
caught the attention of
one of the lord's assistants.
それって…。
ああ。
That means...
Yes. The guard's division is like
the Guardian Shinobi Twelve.
近衛機関は
いわば 守護忍十二士への入り口。
(綱手)これは よほどのことだぞ。
This means a lot.
すごい…。
Amazing...
それで シカマルは？
申し出を受けたんですか？
Then did Shikamaru...?
Accept the offer?
(綱手)アイツときたら…。
That boy...
(アスマ)お前…
大名の件 断ったんだって？
I heard you rejected
the Feudal Lord's offer.
(シカマル)まあ。
Yeah...
(アスマ)外の世界を見るのも
悪くないと思うがな。
It's not a bad idea to experience
the world outside.
オレも 守護忍十二士での経験が
あればこそ➡
I don't think I'd be here now...
今のオレがあると
思わないでも ないけどな。
if I had not been part of
the Guardian Shinobi Twelve.
オレは変わらないよ。
It doesn't matter.
これからも
めんどくさいことは ごめんだ。
I hate tedious stuff
and that won't change in the future.
フンッ！
ただ…。
It's just that...
なんていうか チョウジや いのや
今の小隊の連中や…。
How should I put it...
It's because I'm concerned about
Choji and Ino...
and the other guys in the unit.
And well, Naruto...
まあ ナルトや
気になってしようがねえから➡
So I'm just hanging around.
里にいるだけっていうか…。
そうか… お前にも
火の意志ってやつがあったんだな。
I see...
You also have the Will of Fire.
火の意志って
三代目が言っていた？
The Will of Fire...
The thing the Third used to talk about?
そうだ。 この里を守ろうっていう
強い意志のことだ。
That's right. It refers to the strong will
of wanting to protect this village.
そんな 大げさなことじゃねえよ。
It's nothing that noble.
照れるな！
Don't be shy.
気になるから守りたい。
そうなんだろう？
You're concerned about them,
so you want to protect them, right?
同じ 木ノ葉の忍だから
めんどくせぇけど➡
We're all Ninja of the Leaf.
It's bound to happen, even though
it's not really my thing.
しようがないんじゃないの？
(アスマ)その火の意志が
里を照らすんだって。
The Will of Fire shines upon the village.
まあ 親父の受け売りだがな。
Well, that's what my dad told me.
じゃあ いつか
アスマも照らしてやるよ。
Then, I'll shine light on you someday.
Just kidding.
(なんてな。
フッ！))
《サクラ : あのシカマルなら心配ない。
No need to worry about Shikamaru.
何よりこれは
アスマ先生の弔い合戦。
Besides, this is the battle to
avenge Asuma Sensei.
万全の計算をして
シカマルは 敵に挑んでいるはず》
Shikamaru should be fighting the enemy
with a perfect plan.
(飛段)動く… 動くぜ！
I can move...!
Damn it...
(シカマル)クソッ！
お前も ジャシン様を信仰していれば➡
If you had believed in Lord Jashin,
you may have gotten a helping hand
in your time of need.
ピンチに救いの手があったかもな。
今から ジャシン様を信じるなら
その改心に免じて…。
If you'll believe in Lord Jashin
from now on...
to honor your reformation...
フンッ！ 許すわけねえだろ！ バーカ！
As if I'd forgive you! Idiot!
うぅっ！
I don't care about his forgiveness.
(シカマル)そんなもんに
許してもらわなくても結構だぜ！
くっ！
影寄せの術！
Shadow Pull Jutsu!
や… 野郎！
Y-You...!
フンッ！ まだ
これくらいのチャクラは残ってるぜ！
I still have this much...Chakra left.
野郎！
You...
な 何しやがる！
へっ！ 見てろって！
Wh-What are you doing?!
Just watch...
(飛段)なにっ!?
What?!
どういうことだ？
いつの間に こんな…。
What happened?!
When did you do this...?!
前もって ここに仕掛けを
準備していただけのことだ。
I had this trap prepared beforehand.
《コイツ… がむしゃらに
オレら２人を離したんじゃなく➡
So he didn't just separate us on a whim,
but he purposely lured me here?
オレを ここに誘い込んだってのか？
だとすりゃ
ここまでが コイツの計算!?》
Then...this was all his plan!
When you curse someone,
you dig two holes.
人を呪わば穴二つ。
わかるか？ この意味。
知るかよ！
You know what that means?
What?!
人を呪って殺そうとすればな
その報いで テメエも殺されるから➡
If you curse to kill someone,
you also get killed in retribution,
葬る穴が
２つ必要になるってことよ。
that's why you need
two holes for the burial.
You cursed and killed my teacher.
お前は オレの師を呪い殺した。
テメエだけ のうのうと
はしゃいでいられると思うな！
Don't think I'll let you
get away free and easy.
そいつが テメエの墓穴だ。
This hole is your grave.
ハハッ… オレは死なねえ！
I am not gonna die...
Even if my body is dismembered
into pieces and only my head remains,
体を バラバラにされて
首一つになろうが➡
必ず 這いずり出て➡
I am going to drag myself out
and eat your throat!
テメエのノド元に
くらいつきに行ってやる！
あっ！
What?
(飛段)なんだ？ シカ？
Deer?
この森は 火の国でも
特別な場所でな➡
These woods are a special place
in the Land of Fire.
オレたち一族だけが
立ち入ることを許されてる。
Our family is the only ones allowed in.
No one else comes here.
他には 誰も来ない！
あぁ…。
(シカマル)オレたち一族が
ずっと お前を見張っておく！
Our family will always
keep an eye on you.
You did a great job, Shikamaru.
よくやったな シカマル。
Yeah...
あぁ。
うん？
(アスマ)ふう～！
オレの火の意志 お前に託したぞ。
My Will of Fire...is now yours.
テ… テメエ… 何 つけてんだよ!!
You, why...are you turning that on?
(シカマル)火の意志だ。
It's the Will of Fire...
the will to protect our village.
オレたち 里を守ろうという
強い意志だ。
《シカマル : さよなら… 先生》
Good bye...Sensei.
多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
多重影分身…。
Multiple Shadow Clones...
(角都)そうか。
お前が 九尾の人柱力か。
I see... You are the Nine-Tailed Jinchuriki.
状況説明と
敵の能力を教えてください。
What's the situation
and the enemy's power?
敵は 暁 ２人。
The enemy is two Akatsuki.
さっきも言ったように
１人は シカマルが応戦中。
As I said before,
Shikamaru is fighting one of them...
で もう１人が目の前にいる。
and the other one is in front of us.
コイツは 分裂する能力がある。
This guy has the power to split.
(カカシ)あの両肩の面が 本体から
抜け出して分裂するんだが➡
Those two masks on the shoulders
split from the torso.
その面 一つひとつに心臓があり
独立して行動する。
Each mask has a separate heart
and moves independently.
ヤツは 初め
５つの心臓を持っていた。
He originally had five hearts.
He lost two and has only three now.
今は ２つ減らして あと３つだ。
どういうことです？
What do you mean?
もう 二度 殺してるってことだ。
I've killed him twice already.
ヤツは あと３度 殺さないと
倒れない。
We need to kill him three more times
to finish him off.
それに 中距離タイプで
あらゆる性質変化を使う。
Plus, he's an intermediate
distance fighter
and can use
multiple Change in Chakra Natures.
《どうりで
先輩が手こずるわけだ…》
No wonder you were
having a hard time...
ナルト！
Naruto!
ちゃんと聞いてたってばよ！
I heard it!
ナルト！
Naruto!
It's no use charging in recklessly!
やみくもに
突っ込んでも ダメだってば！
フン…。
うわっ…。
影分身だけか？
それでは勝てんぞ。
You can only make Shadow Clones?
You can't beat me with that.
《あの攻撃スピードと
戦闘スタイルからして➡
Based on his attack speed
and fighting style,
陽動には 最低でも
影分身が３人いるってばよ》
I need at least three Shadow Clones
to distract him.
《まず 影分身の経験値を
オリジナルの中に情報として蓄積。
He gathered each clones' experience
and processed it...
それに基づいたシミュレーションの作成。
and based on that,
he formed a simulation.
影分身の使い方が
さらに うまくなっている…》
His ability to use
Shadow Clones has advanced.
多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
影分身を３体…。
Three Shadow Clones...
何なの？ あれ…。
What's...that?
すごい高音…。
な… なんてチャクラだ…。
What a...high pitched...Chakra!
アイツら 何を…。
What...are they...?
((なんとか ここまでは…
形にしたってばよ。
I tried my best...
to build it up to her
よし。 どれほどのもんか
オレの螺旋丸と ぶつけ合う。
用意しろ。
なっ… えっ!?
でも そんなことしたら…
どうなるの？
術が完成に近づいているなら➡
オレの螺旋丸など
ひとたまりもない。
さあ いくぞ！
(カカシ)四代目…！
《何だ あの術は…
あれをくらったら やばい…。
絶対に ダメだ…》
風遁 螺旋手裏剣！
(ヒナタ)あっ あっ… 冷たっ！
(キバ)ああ… ヒマだ！
オレたち 第八班の待機命令は
いつまで続くんだよ。
(シノ)仕方がない。
なぜなら 紅先生は
心に大きな傷を負っているからだ。
わかってるよ！
わかってるけどよ…。
(キバ)第十班は アスマ先生の仇を
討つために出かけちまったし➡
ナルトのヤツも新術を完成させるとかで
修業してるみてぇだし。
ナルト君… がんばってるんだ。
お前 顔 赤いぞ。
あっ… なんでもない！
なんでもないよ…。
ふ～ん… なら いいけどよ。
じゃ 紅先生のとこ寄って帰るぜ。
(キバ)いくぞ！ 赤丸！
(赤丸)ワン ワン！
キ… キバ君！
(ヒナタ)待ってよ！ キバ君！
また 独りか…。
独り占めするには
この空は広すぎる…。